你好 阿曼斯基
Hello, Armansky.
- 你去哪里了 - 旅行
- Where have you been? - Travelling.
布隆维斯特一直在试图联系你 他每个月至少打一次电话
Blomkvist's been trying to get hold of you. He calls at least once a month.
我会在合同上签上你的名字 - 那么你住在哪里
- I'll put your name on the contract. - So where do you live?
在别的地方
Somewhere else.
有多位知名客户的证明
have proof of a number of prominent customers.
我们将会踩到几个脚趾
We'll be stepping on a few toes.
我需要一个叫扎拉的黑帮成员的信息
I need information on a gangster called Zala.
达格
Dag?
凶器属于尼尔斯·埃里克·比约曼
The murder weapon belongs to Nils Erik Bjurman.
我们设法提取了两个指纹
We managed to lift two prints.
- 她叫什么名字 - 丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
- Does she have a name? - Lisbeth Salander.
- 93年的一份警方报告 萨兰德 - 把它们放在我乡下的家里
- A police report from '93. Salander. - keep them at my country home.
猜猜谁是她的监护人 尼尔斯·比约曼
And guess who's her guardian. Nils Bjurman.
- 有些东西你应该看看 - 这是一个很好的谋杀动机
- There's something you should see. - It's a fine motive for murder.
我们马上就要公布名单了
We're on the verge of publishing the names
那些绝对不想要这种关注的人
of people who definitely don't want this kind of attention.
扎拉是谁 - 不知道
- Who is Zala? - don't know.
- 警察不应该有这份名单吗 - 不
- Shouldn't the police have this list? - No.
我需要你的帮助 保罗 我需要找到她的一个朋友 米里亚姆·吴
I need your help, Paolo. need to find a friend of hers, Miriam Wu.
我没有杀达格和米娅 如果你想帮我就去找扎拉
I didn't kill Dag and Mia. Find Zala if you want to help me.
玩火的女孩
THE GIRL WHO PLAYED WITH FIRE
第四部分
PART 4
我习惯了被猛烈抨击 但这家伙是另一回事
I'm used to getting slammed, but this guy was something else.
- 他长什么样 - 像个金发坦克
- What did he look like? - Like a blond tank.
我没跟你开玩笑 纯粹的肌肉
I'm not kidding you. Pure muscle.
- 你以前从未见过他 - 从未见过
- And you've never seen him before? - Never.
他像一个拳击手一样移动 举起他的拳头
He moved like a boxer, held his fists up right.
- 但他有点空虚 - 就像吸毒后兴奋起来
- But he was kind of vacant. - Like hopped up on drugs?
不 这才是最奇怪的地方
No, that's what was so strange.
我可以在他想要的时候 尽可能地猛烈地打他
could hit him when wanted, as hard as could
就像他上过拳击课 但并没有真正用心
It was like he'd taken boxing lessons but not really paid attention.
这件事还有一件奇怪的事
There's another weird thing about this.
那是什么
What's that?
在他的脸上重重地打了一拳 大约一百次
punched him hard in the face, about a hundred times.
但什么都没发生
But nothing happened.
就好像他什么都没感觉到
It was like he didn't feel anything.
- 你好 请来1B病房 - 那是更低的位置
- Hello. Ward 1B, please. - That's further down.
谢谢
Thank you.
扬·布布兰斯基
Jan Bublanski.
- 你感觉怎么样 - 棒极了
- How are you feeling? - Fabulous.
我去找个房间 我们可以私下谈谈
I'll find us a room where we can talk in private.
- 米里亚姆·吴怎么样了 - 医生还和她在一起
- How's Miriam Wu? - The doctor's still with her.
她长得像我 但他们不是冲着她来的 他们想要丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
She looks like me, but they weren't after her. They want Lisbeth Salander.
所有这一切都与一个名叫扎拉的人有关
All this has something to do with a man named Zala.
达格·斯文森将他与谋杀妓女伊琳娜联系在一起
Dag Svensson tied him to the murder of a prostitute named Irina.
- 她被发现死在一条运河里 - 比约曼呢
- She was found dead in a canal. - What about Bjurman?
好吧 达格沉默了 但谁会杀了萨兰德的监护人
OK that Dag was silenced, but who'd kill Salander's guardian?
好的 不要把这些都拼凑在一起
OK, don't have it all pieced together.
但扎拉和比约曼之间肯定有联系
But there must be a link between Zala and Bjurman.
再见
Goodbye.
你在对我撒谎
You lied to me!
- 你上次骗了我 就在这里 - 是吗 7
- You lied to me last time was here! - Did 1?7
是 你和比约曼在70年代为安全警察工作
Yes. You and Bjurman worked for the security police in the '70s.
你假装你不认识他
You made out you didn't know him.
我不需要告诉你我和谁共事过
don't have to tell you who I've worked with.
你知道扎拉是谁吗
Do you know who Zala is?
- 这么说你知道了 - 我没这么说
- So you do know? - didn't say that.
我没这么说
didn't say that.
你想要什么
What do you want?
他是本台记者达格·斯文森名单上的名字之一
He's one of the names on our reporter Dag Svensson's list.
他感兴趣的人之一
One of the people he was interested in.
如果知道一些关于扎拉的事情 对你来说有什么价值
If know anything about Zala, what would it be worth to you?
这取决于你知道些什么
It depends on what you know.
你会考虑在你的报告中忘了我吗
Would you consider forgetting me in your report?
- 唱一点 - 没有
- Sing a little bit. - No.
- 来吧 唱吧 - 让我们看看你是什么做的
- Come on, sing. - Show us what you're made of.
- 不是这里 - 这是我们的站
- Not here. - It's our stop.
赶快
Come on.
多少钱
How much?
一半 20万美元 用现金支付
Half. 200 grand. In cash.
好的
OK.
- 我得去拿钱了 - 什么时候
- I'll have to go and get the money. - When?
- 我们现在就可以做 - 我会做的
- We can do it right now. - I'll do it.
顺便问一下 它进行得怎么样
By the way, how did it go?
- 什么怎么样 - 你什么意思
- How did what go? - What do you mean?
避暑别墅
The summer house.
比约曼家 你要把它烧了
Bjurman's place. You were going to torch it.
我们正要 .. 我们还没有抽出时间来做这件事
We were just about... We haven't got around to it yet.
- 你没有 - 我们现在就去 然后拿到你的钱
- You haven't? - We'll do it now. And get your money.
我们一会儿就把钱带回来 好吗
We'll be back with the money in a little while, OK?
我就在这里等着
I'll wait right here.
妈的 这不是那个萨兰德婊子吗
Shit, if it isn't that Salander bitch.
我们一直在到处找你
We've been looking all over for you.
就连那个女同性恋都不知道你在哪里 至少她是这么说的
Not even that dyke knew where you were. At least that's what she said.
- 是吗 玛姬 - 看看她
- Isn't that so, Magge? - Look at her.
她看起来真的需要好好操一把
She looks like she could use a good honest fuck.
别挡我的路 呆子
Get out of my way, goon.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
嗨 你的第一个任务是辨认那个高大的金发男人
Hi. Your first job is to identify the large, blond man
以及他绑架和袭击米里亚姆·吴的秃头同伴
and his bald companion who kidnapped and assaulted Miriam Wu.
第二项工作是检查被谋杀记者电脑上的赌客名单
The second job is to go through the list of punters that was on the murdered reporter's computer.
- 赌客名单 - 索尼娅 希望你来负责
- List of punters? - Sonia, want you to take charge of that.
尼克拉斯 你来帮忙
Niklas, you help.
第三 我们必须把重点放在一个叫扎拉的无名男子身上
Thirdly, we must focus on an unknown man called Zala.
- 那是你的工作 法斯特 - 我的工作
- That's your job, Faste. - My job?
得到特别调查组对 的协助 坚持住 坚持住 你在玩什么把戏
Get assistance from the special investigative group on... Hang on. Hang on. What's your game?
- 我的游戏 - 是的
- My game? - Yes.
- 什么比赛 - 我们的重点必须是莉斯贝丝·萨兰德
- What game? - Our focus must be on Lisbeth Salander.
我们必须检查所有的次要线索
We have to check all secondary leads.
胡说八道
That's bullshit.
怎么 你觉得所有关于她的精神病学报告都是笑话吗
What, do you think all psychiatric reports on her are a joke?
- 她和凶器有关 - 我知道
- She's tied to the murder weapon! - know.
有迹象表明 她和吴大克是妓女
There are indications that she and that dyke Wu are prostitutes
如果她不是女同性恋性崇拜的一部分 我就完了
and I'll be fucked if she's not part of some lesbian sex cult.
闭嘴 你痴迷于那个同性恋的角度 这不是专业的
Shut it. You're obsessed with that gay angle. It's not professional.
所以忽视她是个暴力精神病的事实是专业的吗
So it's professional to ignore the fact that she's a violent psycho?
- 他妈的怎么回事 - 够了
- What the fuck...? - That's enough.
太对了
Damned right.
还有别的什么吗
Did you have anything else?
我不希望任何人提到保罗·罗伯托 如果媒体听说了这件事 好的
don't want anyone mentioning Paolo Roberto. If the media hears of it... OK.
你们谁是泄密者
Which one of you is the leak?
谁?
Who?
一位名叫托尼·斯卡拉的记者采访了一名警察 这名警察告诉了他米里亚姆·吴的情况
A reporter called Tony Scala has spoken to a cop who told him about Miriam Wu.
什么 你在开玩笑吧
What? You're joking.
文章将消息来源描述为“她”
The article describes the source as a "she".
报纸争相了解保罗·罗伯托在这件事中扮演的角色
The papers are clamouring to know Paolo Roberto's role in this.
- 不是我 - 她说她不是泄密者
- It wasn't me! - She says she's not the leak.
莫迪格 不能证明你在泄露信息
Modig, can't prove that you are leaking information.
但我已经对你失去了所有的信心
But I've lost all confidence in you.
她说她不是泄密者
She says she's not the leak.
- 我要让你退出这个案子 - 你现在不能这么做
- I'm taking you off the case. - You can't do that now.
这周剩下的时间休息一下吧 你将在星期一被分配新的任务
Take the rest of the week off. You'll be assigned new duties on Monday.
索尼娅
Sonja...
你现在还在负责这个案子 我的命令
You're still on the case for now. My orders.
去千禧年 和Mikael Blomkvist再聊一聊
Go to Millennium and have another chat with Mikael Blomkvist.
让他帮你检查达格·斯文森的硬盘 他们有一份副本
Ask him to help you go through Dag Svensson's hard drive. They have a copy.
- 还没有和尼克拉斯说过话 - 把这个交给我吧
- haven't spoken to Niklas yet. - Leave that to me.
好吧
Well...
所以
So...
正确的
Right.
火已经熄灭了
The fire's out.
他们带了一条狗来闻瓦砾中的身体
They brought in a dog to sniff out any dead bodies in the rubble.
- 有吗 - 没有
- And were there any? - No, there weren't.
但当我们休息一下让狗的鼻子休息一下时 训导员散步了一下 把它放了下来
But when we took a break to give the dog's nose a rest, the handler took a walk and let him loose.
他追踪到了什么东西
He tracked something.
所以我们挖出了现场 发现了一具被切成六半的身体
So we dug up the spot and found a body, chopped into six parts.
- 电锯 - 什么
- A chainsaw? - What?
电锯 身体会不会是用电锯切开的
Chainsaw. Could the body have been cut up with a chainsaw?
保罗·罗伯托说 米里亚姆曾受到过一次威胁
Paolo Roberto said Miriam had been threatened with one.
没有那么仔细地看过
haven't looked that closely.
我们刚刚开始挖掘 他们还在搭帐篷
We've just started to dig it up, and they're still erecting the tent.
我会派尼克拉斯过去
I'll send Niklas over.
- 我相信你再喝一杯就行了 - 很好
- I'm sure you can do with one more. - Good.
尼克拉斯
Niklas?
嗨 尼可拉斯 我是托尼
Hi, Niklas. Tony here.
谢谢你的帮助 我想知道你还有没有 托尼·斯卡拉 - 什么
Thanks for the help. was wondering if you've got anymore... - Tony Scala? - What?
我将从看到达格要揭露的赌徒开始
I'll start by seeing the punters Dag was going to expose.
好的 那么让我们来看看
Good. So let's take a look.
斯坦·法尔斯特伦完蛋了 他完蛋了
Sten Fahlstrém's done. He's done.
卡尔·彼得森完蛋了
Karl Petersson's done.
- 那Per-Ake Sandstrém呢 - Dag质问过他
- What about Per-Ake Sandstrém? - Dag had confronted him.
那个保安警察呢 比耶克
And that security police guy? Bjérck.
比耶克和比约曼打成平手
There's a tie between Bjérck and Bjurman.
我和比耶克还没完呢
I'm not through with Bjérck yet.
- 比耶雷克 - 布隆维斯特 你没回我电话
- Bjérek. - Blomkvist. You didn't get back to me.
你想要什么
What do you want?
明天是我关于达格和米娅被杀的新闻发布会
Tomorrow's my press conference about the murders of Dag and Mia.
计划讨论我们的性交易文章
plan to discuss our sex trade article.
你是我唯一的赌徒
You're the only punter I'm fingering.
- 你答应给我时间的 - 是的 但是 我改变主意了
- You promised to give me time. - Yes, but changed my mind.
如果你举行新闻发布会 你永远不会知道扎拉的事
If you hold that press conference, you'll never learn about Zala.
这是可能的 但那就不再是我的问题了
That's possible, but then it won't be my problem anymore.
你得跟警方的官方调查人员谈谈
You'll have to talk to the official police inquiry
- 以及其他媒体 - 站在那里别动
- and the rest of the media. - Just hold up there.
我想指控尼克拉斯违反保密规定 但Ekstrém没有
want to charge Niklas with breach of confidentiality, but Ekstrém doesn't.
- 他会怎么样 - 我们把他赶出来了
- What'll happen to him? - We kicked him out.
他说他这么做是为了钱
He said he did it for money.
- 他说他手头拮据 - 他正在翻新他的房子
- He said he was hard up. - He's renovating his house.
晨会结束五分钟后 他给托尼·斯卡拉打了电话
He called Tony Scala five minutes after the morning meeting.
不久之后 斯卡拉把这一切都放到了网上
Shortly afterwards Scala had put it all out on the net.
你正式回到这个案子上了 索尼娅
You are formally back on the case, Sonja.
不过 如果我是你 我不会指望埃克斯特雷姆道歉
Though I wouldn't expect an apology from Ekstrém if I were you.
不是的
No.
我不是一个谈论我的上级的狗屎 但他可以去吊死
I'm not one to talk shit about my superiors, but he can go hang.
他的名字是亚历山大·萨拉琴科 但大家都叫他扎拉
His name is Alexander Zalachenko, but he's known as Zala.
他是谁 在哪里能找到他
Who is he? Where can find him?
- 他不是你想找的人 - 但是 我想
- He's not someone you want to find. - But want to.
- 他实际上并不存在 - 你是什么意思
- He doesn't actually exist. - What do you mean?
这是机密信息
This is classified information.
希望你能理解 我的名字必须保密
hope you understand that my name must be kept secret.
我已经同意了
I've agreed to that already.
萨拉琴科1940年出生于苏联
Zalachenko was born in 1940, in the Soviet Union.
他的父母都在第二次世界大战中去世
Both of his parents died in World War Two.
- 希望你知道GRU是什么 - 他们的军事情报部门
- expect you know what the GRU was? - Their military intelligence service.
他在那里有很不错的职业生涯
He had quite a career there.
精通六种语言 擅长伪装 和生存
Fluent in six languages, an expert at camouflage... and survival.
所以他被允许留下来
So he was allowed to stay.
GRU的高级官员以前从未叛逃到瑞典
No senior officer of GRU had ever defected to Sweden before.
比约曼适合在哪里
Where does Bjurman fit in?
嗯 那时候我们还年轻 25 30
Well, we were young back then. 25, 30.
完全没有资格照顾像萨拉琴科这样的人
Completely unqualified to take care of a man like Zalachenko.
1976年 他在选举日现身
He showed up on election day, in 1976.
警察总部几乎空无一人
Police headquarters was practically empty.
几乎每个人都外出执行特别任务
Nearly everyone was out on special duty.
当时他随叫随到 以为自己是个普通的难民
was on call, and thought he was an ordinary refugee.
所以 让比约曼一起来处理文书工作
So brought Bjurman along to manage the paperwork.
比约曼牵涉其中纯属偶然
It was pure chance that Bjurman got involved.
- Chance - 是的 事实上
- Chance? - Yes, actually.
牵牛花
Morning glory.
- 什么 - 它就是这么叫的
- What? - That's what it's called.
- 萨拉琴科在哪里 - 1985年之前一直是他的联系人
- Where is Zalachenko? - was his contact until 1985.
在那之后 被分配到其他任务
After that, was assigned to other duties.
你给了他一个新身份和一个瑞典名字 他的瑞典名字叫什么
You gave him a new identity and a Swedish name. What's his Swedish name?
- 我不会告诉你的 - 来吧
- won't tell you that. - Come on.
我已经告诉过你扎拉是谁 这就是你得到的一切 直到你知道你会信守诺言
I've told you who Zala is and that's all you get until know you'll keep your word.
他犯了三起谋杀罪 警察走错了路
He's committed three murders. The police are on the wrong track.
你为什么这么确定不是利斯贝丝·萨兰德干的
Why are you so sure Lisbeth Salander didn't do it?
我相信是萨拉琴科干的 - 你错了
- believe Zalachenko did it. - You're wrong.
扎拉没有向任何人开枪 他69岁了 是个残疾人
Zala didn't shoot anyone. He's 69 and handicapped.
这家伙需要拐杖 所以他不能到处跑来跑去开枪射击
The guy needs a crutch, so he can't exactly run around shooting people.
他需要打电话给移动服务中心才能找到受害者
He'd need to call the mobility service to get to his victims.
希望不会在报纸上看到我的名字
hope won't be seeing my name in the papers.
你是说莉斯贝丝·萨兰德出现了
So you're telling me that Lisbeth Salander showed up
单枪匹马把几个摩托车手打得落花流水
and beat the shit out of a couple of bikers single-handedly?
是
Yes.
她是由保罗·罗伯托训练的
She's trained by Paolo Roberto.
不管怎样 Magnus“Magge”Lundin的脚上有一处枪伤
Anyway, Magnus "Magge" Lundin has a bullet wound in the foot
面部受伤 鼻梁骨折 两颗牙齿缺失
and injuries to the face, with a broken nose and two missing teeth.
他似乎也有严重的腹股沟疼痛
He also seems to have serious groin pains.
另一个呢 尼米宁
And the other one? Nieminen?
他似乎安然无恙
He seems to be unharmed.
但据打电话给我们的目击者说
But according to the witness there who called us,
她出现时 他正昏迷不醒地躺在地上
he was lying unconscious on the ground when she turned up.
还有一件事 这个马格·伦丁 他的肚子很大 是个秃头
And another thing. This Magge Lundin... He's got a big belly and is bald.
绑架吴美莲的其中一名绑架者是秃顶 有啤酒肚
One of Miriam Wu's kidnappers was bald and had a beer gut.
- 你不是懒惰的一方 看到了吗 - 没有
- You're not on the lazy side, see. - No.
- 我刚认识比耶克 - 很好
- I've just met Bjérck. - Good.
他说完了吗 我们能用他吗
Is he done? Can we use him?
这次不行 他不会被包括在内
Not this time. He's not to be included.
- 什么意思 - 我晚点再告诉你
- What do you mean? - I'll tell you later.
你什么时候来 索尼娅·莫迪格来了
When are you coming? Sonja Modig's here.
他们想让我们帮忙检查达格的材料 我们不能放过任何人
They want our help going through Dag's material. We can't spare anyone.
- 我会在我遇到一个人之后去那里 - 赌客
- I'll be there after I've met someone. - A punter?
不 不是赌客
No, not a punter.
他愿意见你 但如果他不喜欢你 他会把你赶出去的
He's willing to see you. But if he doesn't like you, he'll throw you out.
不能接受采访 不能在媒体上发表任何内容 明白吗
No interviews and nothing in the media, is that clear?
好的
OK.
你是谁 自称是丽斯贝丝·萨兰德的朋友
Who are you, claiming to be a friend of Lisbeth Salander?
我是米凯尔·布隆维斯特 我知道其他记者一直在纠缠你
I'm Mikael Blomkvist. know other reporters have been pestering you,
但我来这里不是为了一篇文章 我是为了莉斯贝丝而来的
but I'm not here about an article. I'm here for Lisbeth's sake.
不要认为利斯贝丝·萨兰德参与了这些谋杀
don't think Lisbeth Salander's involved in these killings.
我认为这一切的幕后黑手是一个叫萨拉琴科的人
think a man named Zalachenko is behind it all.
坐下
Sit down.
萨拉琴科
Zalachenko.
亚历山大·萨拉琴科
Alexander Zalachenko.
你知道他是谁吗
Do you know who he is?
他是丽斯贝丝的父亲
He's Lisbeth's father.
圣斯特凡医院
ST STEFAN'S HOSPITAL
根据我们的谈话 孩子必须被带走
With reference to our conversation, the child must be removed...
谢谢你的来信 同意你对事态的看法
Thank you for your letter. agree with you about the state of affairs...
医学评估将显示孩子患有精神疾病
The medical evaluation will show that the child is mentally ill...
她不太可能在不经意间制造麻烦
...less likely that she will inadvertently cause problems...
提议监禁在圣斯特凡大教堂
...propose incarceration at St Stefan's.
不要担心时间问题 负全部责任
And do not worry about the time. take full responsibility.
您诚挚的 彼得·泰尔博里安 乌普萨拉 1993年3月11日
Yours sincerely, Peter Teleborian. Uppsala, 11th March, 1993.
莉斯贝丝的母亲名叫阿格妮塔·谢兰德
Lisbeth's mother's name was Agneta Sjélander.
当萨拉琴科遇到她时 她只有17岁
She was only 17 when Zalachenko met her.
但他们从未结婚
But they never married.
当利斯贝丝出生时 阿格尼塔将她的名字从Sj6élander改为Salander
When Lisbeth was born, Agneta changed her name from Sj6élander to Salander.
这是一种证明他们是一对情侣的方式
It was a way to demonstrate that they were a couple.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
扎拉 - 萨兰德
Zala - Salander.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
萨拉琴科不怎么在家
Zalachenko wasn't home much.
其他人几乎不知道他在哪里
The others hardly knew where he was.
但他时不时地会出现
But every now and then he'd show up...
在他们伦达格坦的家中
...at their home on Lundagatan.
每一次 这种情况都会发生
And every time, this would happen.
他会喝醉 他会殴打阿格尼塔 性侵她 然后离开
He'd get drunk, he'd beat Agneta, sexually assault her and leave.
这种事已经发生了几十次了
It happened dozens of times.
社会服务机构本应做些什么 但什么也没做
Social services should have done something, but nothing happened.
直到1993年
Not until 1993.
- 然后发生了什么 - 请坐
- What happened then? - Please, sit down.
好的
OK.
丽斯贝丝 年仅12岁
Lisbeth... was 12 years old.
萨拉琴科要离开了
Zalachenko was leaving...
丽斯贝丝很害怕她的母亲会伤害自己
...and Lisbeth was terrified that her mother would harm herself.
她逃学了
She played truant from school.
当利斯贝思发现母亲昏迷在厨房地板上时 萨拉琴科笑了
Zalachenko laughed when Lisbeth found her mother unconscious on the kitchen floor.
他上了他的车 然后他
He got into his car, and he...
但丽斯贝丝紧随其后
But Lisbeth came after him.
她甩了一个 .. 一只装满汽油的牛奶盒盖在他身上 然后点燃了一根火柴
She dumped a... a milk carton full of gasoline over him and then a lit match.
天哪
Oh, my God.
一个男人正坐在他的车里 像火炬一样燃烧
man is sitting in his car... ...and burning like a torch.
这一次是有后果的
This time there were consequences.
莉斯贝丝被送到
Lisbeth was sent to...
儿童精神病院
...a mental institution for children.
她母亲在医院度过了她生命的最后几年
Her mother spent the last years of her life in hospital.
从那以后 她就再也不是自己了
She was never herself after that.
- 她所谓的精神错乱 - 彼得·泰尔博里安
- Her alleged mental disturbance... - Peter Teleborian.
他有责任把她关进监狱
He was responsible for committing her.
- 晚餐时间到了 霍尔格 - 我来帮他一把
- Dinner time, Holger. - I'll give him a hand.
迈克 我们至少可以在一件事上达成一致
Mikael, we can at least agree on one thing.
- 利斯贝思不是一个普通人 - 没有
- Lisbeth is not a normal person. - No.
- 你和她下过象棋吗 - 象棋
- Have you ever played chess with her? - Chess?
是 她的记忆力很好
Yes. She has a photographic memory.
是的 知道
Yes, know.
有些事你不知道
There's something you don't know.
关于雷恩的事
About Reine.
斯德哥尔摩的冷血谋杀案 埃夫特斯奈克
Cold-blooded murder in Stockholm, in Eftersnack.
今天 一名35岁左右的男子在S附近的一所避暑别墅被枪杀
A man in his mid 30s was shot today at a summer home near Strdngnés.
他腿部中弹 但情况并不危急
He had been shot in the legs but is not in a critical condition.
警方拒绝透露细节 但表示这其中存在关联
The police decline to go into details but say there is a connection
与一周前发生的三起谋杀案有关
to the three murders that took place a week ago.
警方今晚将举行记者招待会
The police will be holding a press conference this evening.
在我们最新的公告中有更多关于这一点的信息
More on that in our late bulletin.
现在是一些交通警报
And now some traffic alerts.
一辆急救车正从S高速驶向萨瓦韦尔乔
An emergency vehicle is travelling at speed from Sédertélje to Svavelsjo.
如果你在这一地区 请注意
If you are in the area, please be aware...
Teleborian和Bjérck肯定有某种合作协议
Teleborian and Bjérck must have had some kind of cooperation agreement.
我不明白为什么这么多年你什么都不做
don't understand why you didn't do anything during all those years.
是利斯贝思的监护人
was Lisbeth's guardian.
所以她只是长长的队伍中的一个
So she was just one in a long line...
有问题的男孩和女孩
...of boys and girls with problems.
Teleborian宣称利斯贝思有精神病
Teleborian declared that Lisbeth was psychotic
可以在圣斯特凡医院得到最好的照顾
and could receive the best possible care at St Stefan's.
我相信了他 当然 相信了他
believed him. Of course believed him.
比耶克呢
And Bjérck?
他想要她承诺
He wanted her committed.
为她的事业辩护
defended her cause.
我不想让她被关在某个机构里度过一生
didn't want her to spend her life incarcerated in some institution.
因此 妥协是对无能的宣示
So the compromise was a declaration of incompetency.
并被指定为她的监护人
And was appointed her guardian.
别责备自己了 你是为数不多的支持她的人之一
Don't blame yourself. You were one of the few who stood up for her.
但我明白她为什么会和当局和心理学家有矛盾
But can see why she has issues with the authorities and psychologists.
当你中风的时候
When you had your stroke...
你认为比约曼得到这份工作只是偶然的吗
Do you think Bjurman got the job just by chance?
- 没有 - 没有
- No. - No.
我也是
Me neither.
媒体对保罗·罗伯托牵涉其中的猜测甚嚣尘上
There's wild media speculation about Paolo Roberto's involvement in this.
我们可能会收到大量关于链接的问题
We'll probably get loads of questions about links here and there.
因此 我们必须专注于关于利斯贝丝·萨兰德的问题
So we must focus on questions concerning Lisbeth Salander.
这是我们从公众那里得到关于她下落的线报的机会
This is our chance to get tip-offs from the public as to her whereabouts
这样我们才能打破僵局
so we can break this deadlock.
嗨
Hi.
亚历山大·萨拉琴科这个名字对你有什么意义吗
Does the name Alexander Zalachenko mean anything to you?
- 没有 我很快就会有一个新闻发布会 - 又名扎拉 你知道这个名字
- No. I've got a press briefing soon. - Aka Zala. You know that name.
亚历山大·萨拉琴科是利斯贝思·萨兰德的父亲
Alexander Zalachenko is Lisbeth Salander's father.
1993年 她向他扔了一枚燃烧弹 警方对此事进行了调查
She threw a fire bomb at him in 1993, and the police investigated the matter.
- 是安全警察 - 为什么会这样
- It was the security police. - Why is that?
因为亚历山大·萨拉琴科为他们工作
Because Alexander Zalachenko worked for them.
他们不想让它公之于众 你看 他并不是正式存在的
They didn't want it made public. He doesn't officially exist, you see.
- 你从哪里得到这些信息的 - 我希望你能找到这些文件
- Where did you get this information? - want you to find the files.
他们一定在那里的某个地方
They've got to be in there somewhere.
我相信这些文件会带我们找到萨拉琴科
believe the files will lead us to Zalachenko.
我相信他和达格和米娅的死有关
And I'm convinced he was involved in Dag and Mia's deaths.
甚至可能是比约曼的死
Possibly even Bjurman's death.
但不可能是莉斯贝丝·萨兰德 对吧
But it couldn't be Lisbeth Salander, right?
枪上有她的指纹
Her prints are on the gun.
- 我知道这看起来很奇怪 - 它真的很棒
- I know It seems strange. - It damn well does.
你们两个是怎么回事 如果她是无辜的 为什么她不站出来
What's up between you two? Why doesn't she come forward if she's innocent?
因为莉斯贝丝是
Because Lisbeth is...
她是个非常注重隐私的人
She's a very private person.
我不喜欢这些针对警方的指控
don't like these allegations against the police.
我们的问题已经够多了 我们不需要什么业余私家侦探的帮助
We have enough problems. We don't need the help of some amateur private eye.
避暑山庄枪击案、保罗·罗伯托案和米里亚姆·吴被绑架案之间有联系吗
Is there a link between the summer house shooting, Paolo Roberto and Miriam Wu's kidnap?
不 没有任何迹象表明Salander参与了对Miriam Wu的绑架
No, there is nothing to suggest that Salander was involved in the kidnapping of Miriam Wu.
你仍然认为利斯贝思对公众构成威胁吗
Do you still regard Lisbeth as posing a public threat?
她开枪打死了一个人 她有武器
She shot a man. She's armed.
所以很明显我们想要联系上她
So obviously we'd like to get hold of her.
你知道是谁绑架了米里亚姆·吴吗
Do you know who kidnapped Miriam Wu?
我会把这个问题交给简·布布兰斯基
I'll turn that question over to Jan Bublanski.
关于今天的枪击案 我们已经确认了一名男子
In connection with today's shooting, we have identified a man
可能是他在绑架未遂时开的货车
who may have driven the van during the kidnapping attempt.
- 被枪击的那个人 - 拒绝对此发表评论
- The man who was shot? - decline to comment on that.
然而 我们没有关于袭击吴和罗伯托的人的线索
However, we have no leads on the person who assaulted Wu and Roberto.
- 你有描述吗 - 取证素描已经做好了
- Do you have a description? - A forensic sketch has been made.
根据目击者的描述
Based on witness accounts.
一个身材高大、肌肉发达的人 年龄在35岁左右
A tall man with a muscular build. In his mid to late 30s.
健美运动员类型 一头淡金色短发
Body-builder type. Short, pale blond hair.
媒体将在简报会结束后看到这张照片
The media will have access to this image after this briefing...
- 汽车快递 - 我叫古尼拉·汉森
- AutoExpress? - My name's Gunilla Hansson.
我的狗被碾压了 那个混蛋开着你的一辆车
My dog's been run over and the bastard was driving one of your cars.
听到这个我很难受
Sorry to hear that.
想要他的名字这样 就可以要求赔偿
want his name so can claim compensation.
- 你报告了吗 - 没有 我想友好地解决
- Have you reported it? - No, want to settle amicably.
除非警方报警 否则不能公布任何客户的姓名
can't release any customer's name unless a police report's been made.
- 但是 听着 他碾压了我的狗 - 对不起 我们需要一份警方报告
- But, look, he ran over my dog. - Sorry. We need a police report.
他妈的
Shit.
警方尚未逮捕这名30多岁的持枪女子
The police have not yet apprehended the armed woman in her late 20s,
枪击案发生后被观察到的人
who was observed after the shooting
在Strdngnds郊区 乘坐摩托车离开现场
on the outskirts of Strdngnds, leaving the scene on a motorcycle.
某些事实表明这是一场黑社会纠纷
Certain facts indicate an underworld dispute.
他们一点都不明白
They haven't understood a damn thing!
布布兰斯基不会听的 他们在追查错误的线索
Bublanski won't listen. They're chasing the wrong lead.
如果警察逮捕利斯贝思 所有的地狱都可能逃脱
If the police arrest Lisbeth, all hell could break loose!
- 你要去哪里 - 回家
- Where are you going? - Home!
- 要我一起去吗 - 不 我不是个好伙伴
- Want me to come along? - No, I'm not good company.
你不一定要成为一个好伙伴
You don't have to be good company.
我是伊斯贝思 我知道萨拉琴科是谁 帕姆格伦告诉我的
I isbeth, I know who Zalachenko is. Palmgren told me.
我知道泰尔博里安做了什么 也知道你为什么被关在诊所里
I know what Teleborian did and why you were locked up in that clinic.
知道是谁杀了达格和米娅 但不知道比约曼在哪里
know who killed Dag and Mia but not where Bjurman fits in.
请联系我 我们可以解决这个问题
Please contact me. We can solve this.
感谢你成为我的朋友
THANK YOU FOR BEING MY FRIEND
是我 好吗
It's me, OK?
就是这个人吗 他长得是这个样子吗
Is this the guy? Is that what he looked like?
他太可怕了 他是个怪物
He was awful. He was a monster.
上帝啊 我太抱歉了
Christ. I'm so sorry.
他们在找你 你知道这一点 不是吗
They were looking for you. You do realise that, don't you?
你做了什么
What have you done?
Paolo说Blomkvist联系了他 试图联系你
Paolo said Blomkvist contacted him, trying to get hold of you.
- 你们两个怎么了 - 我得走了
- What's going on between you two? - I've got to go.
你们打算去哪儿?
Where are you going?
- 还有一些未完成的事情 - 该死的 丽斯贝丝
- have some unfinished business. - Damn it, Lisbeth!
有人来过这里
Someone was in here!
一个身材矮小 金发碧眼的人 跑掉了
Someone short, blond, who ran off.
我会带点东西来帮你入睡的
I'll be back with something to help you sleep.
很久以前就应该这么做了
should have done it a long time ago.
进去 去吧
Inside! Go on!
停止播放
Stop!
- 给我看看你的租房记录 - 他们在电脑上
- Show me your rental records. - They're on the computer.
打开它
Turn it on.
赶快 很好 很容易
Come on. Nice and easy.
打开那个储物柜
Open that locker.
把你手机给我
Give me your phone.
上车吧 去做吧 这样 就不会伤害你了
Get in. Do it, so won't have to hurt you.
车牌号你在里面还好吗
LICENCE PLATE NUMBER Are you OK in there?
- 你的租房合同在哪里 - 一个红色活页夹 在我桌子上方
- Where are your rental contracts? - A red binder, above my desk.
我找到了我要找的东西 我很快就会离开这里
I've found what I'm looking for. I'll be out of here soon.
需要租车
need to rent a car.
一辆蓝色的高尔夫 24小时的租金是多少
A blue Golf. What's the rental for 24 hours?
345克朗
345 kronor.
这是一万块 你就能拿回车了
Here's ten grand. And you'll get the car back.
感谢你成为我的朋友
THANK YOU FOR BEING MY FRIEND
你好?
Hello?
嗨 我是米里亚姆 米利亚姆·吴
Hi, it's Miriam. Miriam Wu.
你能来医院一趟吗
Could you come to the hospital?
- 她来过这里 什么时候 - 几个小时前
- She was here? When? - A few hours ago.
她有没有说她要去哪里
Did she say where she was going?
不是的
No.
不 她不会的
No, she wouldn't.
如果她找到那个怪物 她就不能带走他了 他会杀了她的
If she finds that monster, she won't be able to take him. He'll kill her.
- 给你 她忘了带这些 - 忘了吗
- Here. She forgot these. - Forgot?
从她的背包里掉出来的
Well, they fell out of her backpack.
我不知道她住在哪里 你是?
have no idea where she lives. Do you?
你要在这里待多久
So how long will you be in here for?
再过几个星期 然后我就坐火车回巴黎
A few weeks, and then I'll take the train back to Paris.
我不想再呆在这里了
don't want to be here anymore.
- 这是什么 - 看起来像信箱钥匙
- What is it? - It looks like a PO box key.
好的
Good.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 这行吗 - 行 谢谢
- Will this do? - Yes. Thanks.
专属公寓
EXCLUSIVE APARTMENT
你好?
Hello?
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth?
哥德堡交通广播 我们有关于190号公路格拉博车祸的消息
Traffic Radio Gothenburg. We have news about the accident in Grabo, road 190.
道路恢复畅通 但车流行驶缓慢
The road is open again, but traffic is moving slowly.
- 你好 - 宝贝 你长得什么样
- Hello. - Baby, what do you look like?
我知道 我看起来糟透了 布隆维斯特在吗
I know, I look terrible. Is Blomkvist around??
他出去玩私家侦探了
He's out playing private eye somewhere.
- 要咖啡吗 - 我要一些 谢谢
- Coffee? - I'd love some, thanks.
这张照片拍摄于17年前 这个人 罗纳德·尼德曼 当时18岁 现在35岁
This was taken 17 years ago. This guy, Ronald Niederman, was 18 at the time, making him 35 now.
- 你从哪里弄到这个的 - 动态 在汉堡
- Where'd you get this? - Dynamic, in Hamburg.
告诉米克那家伙是个差劲的拳击手
told Micke that the guy was a lousy boxer
但他像一个人一样绕圈 所以他一定是受过训练
but that he circled like one, so he must have had training.
给一群欧洲拳击俱乐部发了电子邮件 告诉他们发生了什么 并描述了这个人
emailed a bunch of European boxing clubs, told them what had happened and described the guy.
结果发现他得了一种罕见的疾病
Turns out he has a rare disorder.
先天止痛
Congenital analgesia.
- 那是什么 - 查过了
- What's that? - looked it up.
这是一种遗传性疾病
It's a genetic disorder.
神经冲动没有被正确地传递 你不会感受到痛苦
Nerve impulses aren't transmitted properly. You don't experience pain.
- 对于一个拳击手来说 这是一个多么大的奖励 - - 恰恰相反
- What a bonus for a boxer. - On the contrary.
如果你把手放在电炉上 你会烫伤自己的 很疼
If you put your hand on a hotplate, you'll burn yourself. It hurts.
如果你有这种病 你不会注意到它 直到你闻到烧焦的肉
If you have this disease, you won't notice it till you smell burning flesh.
- 喂 - 嗨 我是马琳
- Yes? - Hi, it's Malin.
- 罗伯托认出了我们的金发巨人 - 那很好
- Roberto's identified our blond giant. - That's good.
- 你在哪里 - 这很复杂
- Where are you? - It's complicated.
- 你听起来心不在焉 - 你说什么
- You sound distracted. - Sorry?
保罗发现了他的名字 是尼德曼
Paolo found out his name. It's Niederman.
太棒了 你有地址吗
Great. Do you have an address?
不是的 我们只有一张17岁的德国照片
No. All we have is a 17-year-old German photo.
你好?米克
Hello? Micke?
看看你能不能找到他的任何记录然后打电话给我
See if you can find any records on him and call me.
你人好吗
Are you nice?
如果你对我好 .. 如果你对我好
If you're nice... If you're nice...
我也会很友善的如果你对我好 .. 友善一点 .. 友善一点
...I'll be nice too. If you're nice... Be nice... Be nice...
- 喂 - 嗨 又是我
- Hello? - Hi, it's me again.
我想我找到了一些东西
think I've got something.
罗纳德·尼德曼没有登记为居住在瑞典 但在1998年
Ronald Niederman is not registered as living in Sweden, but in 1998,
注册了一家名为KAB进口的公司
a company called KAB Import was registered.
好的 - 米克 - 继续
OK... - Micke? - Carry on.
- 一切都好吗 - 不 不好继续
- Is everything OK? - No, it's not. Go on.
董事会主席是卡尔·阿克塞尔·博丁
The chairman of the board is Karl Axel Bodin,
其中一名董事会成员被列为R Niederman
and one of the board members is listed as R Niederman.
1973年1月18日出生 他 有地址吗
Born 18th January, 1973, and he... Any address?
是的
Yes...
Karl-Axel Bodin住在瑞典西部 他的邮寄地址是Gosseberga 612信箱
...Karl-Axel Bodin lives in western Sweden, and his mailing address is PO Box 612, Gosseberga.
“买性爱的男人 ”
"Men who buy sex."
好的 真的很好
Nice. Really nice.
- 埃里卡 - 你去哪里了
- Erika. - Where have you been?
- 来吧 - 怎么了
- Come on. - What's up?
来
Come!
扎拉是丽斯贝丝的父亲
Zala is Lisbeth's father.
一名来自GRU的老苏联杀手 1976年叛逃
An old Soviet hit man from the GRU who defected in 1976.
他现在是个黑帮分子 参与走私 武器 毒品 ..
He's now a gangster, involved in trafficking, weapons, drugs...
是他杀了达格和米娅吗
Did he kill Dag and Mia?
不是亲自来的 他可能派人来了 也许是那个尼德曼
Not personally. He probably sent someone, maybe that Niederman.
我们得把这件事告诉警方
We have to tell the police this.
我试过了 布布兰斯基不会听的
I've tried. Bublanski won't listen.
我想尼德曼就在哥德堡以北的某个地方
think Niederman is somewhere north of Gothenburg.
如果马琳能找到他 丽斯贝丝就能
If Malin can track him down, then Lisbeth can.
现在 利斯贝思正在寻找萨拉琴科
Now Lisbeth is on the hunt for Zalachenko.
- 我不喜欢这个 - 利斯贝思因三起谋杀罪被通缉
- don't like this. - Lisbeth is wanted for triple murder.
如果我们联系警方 他们会部署国家特遣部队
If we contact the police, they'll deploy the National Task Force.
任何事情都有可能发生
And anything could happen.
我们应该尽可能长时间不让警察插手这件事
We should keep the police out of this for as long as we can.
米凯尔
Mikael.
我们不能向警方隐瞒信息 尤其是在谋杀案中
We can't withhold information from the police, not in a murder case.
我们不会的
We won't.
想让你为我做一件事
want you to do something for me.
以下是比约克1993年调查的文件
Here are Bjorck's files from the 1993 investigation.
它包括比约里克和电信人之间关于利斯贝思的信件
It includes correspondence between Bjoérck and Teleborian about Lisbeth.
复印一份 然后把原件寄给布布兰斯基
Make copies and send the originals to Bublanski.
我要去哥德堡 赶在警察之前找到她
I'm going to Gothenburg, to find her before the police do.
我会一直陪在她身边 欠她的
I'm going to be there for her all the way. owe her that.
天哪 请小心
Christ, please be careful.
米克
Micke.
- 给你打包 - 谢谢你
- Package for you. - Thank you.
他会对此感到高兴吗
Would he have been pleased with this?
- 谁 - 达格
- Who? - Dag.
你认为这样对吗
Do you think so?
这似乎太不公平了 他从未在报纸上看到过这一点
It just seems so unfair that he never got to see this in print.
在他付出了所有的努力之后
After all the work he'd put into it.
干杯 敬达格
A toast. To Dag.
为米娅干杯
A toast to Mia.
敬达格和米娅 - 我们需要更多像他们这样的人
- To Dag and Mia. - We need more like them.
你好 爸爸
Hello, Dad.
- 什么事 - 布布兰斯基和莫迪格来了
- Yes? - Bublanski and Modig are here.
他们看了93年关于莉斯贝丝·萨兰德的档案
They have read the files on Lisbeth Salander from '93.
他们想要冈纳·比耶克的地址
And they want Gunnar Bjérck's address.
- 我们应该给他们吗 - 他们可以自己找到的
- Should we give it to them? - They can find it themselves.
这能有多难呢 他们是警察
How hard can it be? They are the police!
让我和他谈谈
Let me speak to him.
布隆库斯特 我想你应该来警局做个正式声明
Blomkuvist, think you should come to the station and make a formal statement.
- 没时间 - 你说什么
- don't have the time. - Sorry?
- 我不在斯德哥尔摩 - 那么你在哪里
- I'm not in Stockholm. - So where are you?
我只是个无知的私家侦探 记得吗
I'm just an ignorant private eye, remember?
你什么时候才能长大 也不认为萨兰德有罪
Grow up. don't think Salander's guilty, either.
让埃里卡接电话
Put Erika back on.
什么事 - 把比耶克的地址给他
- Yes? - Give him Bjérck's address.
我把手机关掉了 这样他们就不能跟踪我了 再见
And I'm switching off my phone, so they can't track me. Bye.
再见
Bye.
我一直在看着你 从四点开始
I've been watching you. Since four o'clock.
没想到你会有勇气展示自己
didn't think you'd have the guts to show yourself.
你成功地触发了每一个警报
You managed to set off every single alarm.
你有运动探测器吗
You've got motion detectors?
两个面朝地面 四个面朝田野
Two facing the grounds, four facing the field.
你看起来像屎一样
You look like shit.
但你有我的眼睛
But you've got my eyes.
疼吗
Does it hurt?
这些年来我一直在想你
I've thought about you over the years.
就像每次 在镜子里看到自己一样
Like every time see myself in the mirror.
- 你应该离我妈妈远点 - 你的母亲
- You should have left my mother alone. - Your mother...
- 你母亲是个妓女 - 不 她没有
- Your mother was a whore. - No, she wasn't.
她在一家杂货店工作 努力维持生计
She worked at a grocery store and tried hard to make ends meet.
无论你喜欢你母亲的什么 你都可以相信
Believe whatever you like about your mother.
但她是个妓女
But she was a whore.
如果你一个人待着 就不会在意了
If you'd left well alone, wouldn't have cared.
恨你
hate you.
- 但是我已经原谅你了 - 胡说 比约曼雇你来杀我
- But I've forgiven you. - Bullshit! Bjurman hired you to kill me.
这是完全不同的 这就是生意
That's completely different. That's business.
你有他想要的这部电影
You had this film he wanted.
并且 有一个适度的商业运作
And have a modest business operation.
他真的强奸了你吗
Did he really rape you?
天哪 这家伙一定很有品味
Christ, the guy must have god-awful taste.
也许我会让尼德曼给你一个好的轴系 看起来你需要它
Maybe I'll ask Niederman to give you a good shafting. Looks like you need it.
你为什么不自己来做呢
Why don't you do it yourself?
坐 坐下
Sit. Sit down!
否则就会像狗一样射杀你
Or will shoot you like a dog.
为什么不给你一个好的轴系呢
Why don't give you a good shafting?
那将是
That would be...
变态
...perverse.
你在哪里找到那个怪胎的
Where did you find that freak?
你是说你还没想明白吗
Do you mean you haven't figured it out?
他们说你是个技术高超的研究员
They say you're a skilled researcher.
但我猜这不是真的
But guess that's not true.
尼德曼在你的小燃烧弹后康复的时候帮助了我
Niederman helped me when was convalescing after your little fire bomb.
现在 它更像是一种伙伴关系
Now it's more of a partnership.
你的意思是说你还没有意识到他是谁
Do you mean to say you haven't realised who he is?
他是你的兄弟
He's your brother.
什么 - 实际上他是你同父异母的兄弟
- What? - Actually, he's your half-brother.
这是很久以前在德国的一次放纵的结果
The result of a fling long ago, in Germany.
最后一次
A last one.
尼德曼也杀了比约曼吗 为什么
Did Niederman kill Bjurman, too? Why?
比约曼是个傻瓜 他有属于我的文件
Bjurman was a fool, and he had documents that belonged to me.
他是为数不多的知道我过去的人之一
He was one of the few people who knew about my past.
我不相信他会守口如瓶
couldn't trust him to keep his mouth shut.
尤其是当那些记者四处打探的时候
Particularly when those journalists were poking around.
这太过分了
It was too much.
他居然愚蠢地告诉我们他有一把手枪
And he was stupid enough to tell us that he owned a pistol.
上面有指纹的手枪
A pistol with fingerprints on it.
你的指纹
Your fingerprints.
你不该碰那把枪的 丽斯贝丝
You shouldn't have touched the gun, Lisbeth.
你太马虎了 警察会找到你的
You've been too sloppy. The police will find you.
哦 天哪 我好害怕
Oh, dear, I'm so scared.
没有向任何人开枪
didn't shoot anybody.
他们可以确定他们想要的该死的人
They can identify who the hell they want.
我只是个可怜的老跛子 对吧
I'm just a poor old cripple, right?
是保安警察把你关进监狱的 不是我
It was the Security Police who had you committed, not me.
他们不会把所有的牌都放在桌子上 哦 不
And they won't be putting all their cards on the table, oh, no.
你仍将是他们所有谋杀案的头号嫌疑犯
You will remain their prime suspect for all those murders.
准备好的?
Ready?
也许我该说点什么
Maybe should say something.
但是 我想我没有什么要对你说的
But don't think have anything to say to you.
- 我也是 - 让我们把这件事做完
- That goes for me, too. - Let's get this over with.
我抓到你了 这对我来说已经足够了 警察今晚会来的
I've nailed you, that's good enough for me. The cops will be here tonight.
犯傻呀
Bullshit!
预计会有一些虚张声势
expected some bluffing.
但你是来杀我的 仅此而已
But you came here to kill me, and that's that.
- 你没有和任何人说过话 - 能给你看点东西吗
- You haven't talked to anyone. - Can show you something?
你过去一个小时所说的一切都已经在网上播出了
Everything you've said for the past hour has been broadcast online.
让我想想
Let me see.
不是的
No.
用这个是不可能的
Not possible with this.
白痴
Idiot!
你在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
看在上帝的份上 昂首挺胸
Head high, for Christ's sake.
我来了
I'm here.
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth...
谢谢你的最新消息
Thanks for the update.